## **DEVU VISWANATH SUMA**

Mississauga, Ontario | +1(647)8674731 | devu.v.suma@gmail.com in







#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

An Experienced Software engineer with a passion for developing innovative programs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organizational success, with 2+ years of Experience in Angular, JavaScript and Nodejs technology industry. I am adaptable and flexible towards responsibilities, a fast learner and always willing to learn new tasks and skills and is also looking to obtain a position that will allow me to utilize my skills in the appropriate areas and has potential for growth as a developer.

- Experience in software development life cycle including Requirement analysis, Design Debugging, Development, Integration, Maintenance and Testing of web-based applications.
- A proven team player and ability to work in a team as well as lead the team to a set goal and passionate about solving problems.
- Strong communication skills and the ability to listen carefully to user feedback to determine modifications for optimal user-function.
- **Experience in Object-Oriented Programming**

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages & Technologies & Frameworks JavaScript, Typescript, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap Angular, React, ¡Query, Node.js, Express.js

**Databases & Platforms** SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MS SQL, MongoDB **IDE & Code Editor** Visual Studio, Eclipse, NetBeans, Visual Studio Code

**Version Control & DevOps tools** GIT, Jira, Azure

**Operating Systems** Windows, Linux/Ubuntu

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineer, Innovation Incubator Advisory Pvt Ltd

July 2019 to Sept 2020

- Developed, tested, and debugged e-commerce application based on user stories, requirements, and design specification.
- Developed Responsive web pages for mobile, tablet and desktop using fluid grid system and CSS Media queries.
- Used NPM for installing required node modules and other published Angular npm modules.
- Worked on the REST/Web API to create the service and tested on Postman and used in Angular.
- Developed the notification module and send notification messages using firebaseRealtime database technology.
- Participated in code reviews with product team and gained feedback from senior engineers and experience in writing custom, scalable code.

# Junior Software Engineer, Revolve 314

June 2018 to July 2019

- Assisting the senior developers with all aspects of software design and coding.
- Trained in creating and updating applications using PHP.
- Working on minor bug fixes.
- Participated in code review and quality assurance activities.

### **EDUCATION**

# Post-Graduation Diploma, Lambton College, Ontario

Jan 2022 to Aug 2023

Computer Software and Database Development

# **Bachelor of Engineering, TKM Institute of Technology**

Aug 2014 to Apr 2018

Computer Science and Engineering

#### **WIL PROJECT**

Mobile Security Services is a service providing website which offers a few security services like Remote video surveillance, fire alarm installation, on-site security guards etc. It has corporate and individual customers based on one time, or permanent contract. And it offers real-time ordering and fulfillment, through this website, customers can register, login and see the list of security services, see, and download the information about the security services and the contracts, place an order, communicate online with the operator, etc.

- Evaluated system requirements and implemented multi-tiered (client, server, and database) web applications to meet client requirements.
- Wrote client-side and server-side user authentication code.
- Integrated google app password for implementing reset password functionality.
- Implemented payment module using stripe.
- Created RESTful web service API's and integrated with client side.
- Implemented Redis cache for better performance.

